A bill on the floor.
一張帳單躺在地上
How did it get here
它怎麼到這裡來的？
and what destiny awaits it ?
什麼樣的命運在等著它？
Sometimes simple questions
有時簡單的問題
don't have simple answers
卻有著不簡單的答案
Let's see…
讓我們看看......
Five main points draw
用五個點
the area where it all happened
連出案發現場
One: Chewing gum
一： 口香糖
We see colour stains on the floor
我們常看到口香糖在地板上的髒汙
but we hardly ever imagine
但我們卻幾乎沒人想像過
that every gum, like every bill,
每個口香糖像每張帳單一樣
has an origin and its own history
都有自己的人生故事
A few streets away, a can: 2
隔幾條街有個罐子，它是第二個點
Once bright and new,
曾經閃閃發亮，
it has gone rusty with time.
但隨著時間侵逐漸黯淡
Like everything in life, I guess
大概就像生命的一切吧
3: A car protected by a cover.
三： 一輛被防塵布蓋著的車
This girl has never seen
這女孩從來沒看過
what's inside the cover.
在布下面到底有什麼。
Every day she walks by and she imagines
她走過的每一天，
something different inside.
她都想像裡面有不同的東西。
An orchestra…
一個管弦樂團...
Or a karate team
或空手道隊躲起來
hiding to surprise her
想給她驚喜
4: A dog leash that draws the finishing line.
四： 描繪終點線的那條狗繩。
In 1989 the company Dogmatich
1989 年 Dogmatich 公司
registered its first model, 10ft long
註冊了第一種款式，10 英尺長
Today Dogmatic offers a wide range of models,
今天 Dogmatic 提供各種不同的尺寸
like this Dogmatic Maxi with
像這個教條 Maxi
a retractable leash for strong dogs.
與牽引器強壯的狗。
5: A knocked out man
五： 在歪掉的紅路燈
in front of a bent traffic light.
前昏過去的男人。
The first time he saw
他第一次看到
the word « knocked out »
昏過去]這個字
was on an Iron Man comic book.
是在鋼鐵人的漫畫上
I should also talk about the three men
我也該談談三個男人
involved in the plot
也參與在這個故事
and the destiny of the bill:
以及帳單的命運裡
We don't know the identity
我們還不知道
of the first yet
第一位的身分
… But we know he must travel
…但我們知道他必須旅行
From here to here
從這裡到這裡
Drawing a line between the two points
畫出兩點之中這一條線
we find it measures 737ft
我們發現它長達737 英尺，
and we go through:
而我們會經過：
Two streets, an alley,
兩條街道，一條巷子，
a butcher's, a supermarket,
一家肉鋪，一家超市，
another street, two courtyards,
另一個街頭，兩座院子，
a laundry, a parking lot
洗衣店、 停車場
and we get to our final destination.
然後我們到達我們最終的目的地。
There waits for him
在那裡等著
our second character: Junior
我們的第二個角色： Junior
From now on JCT
從現在起 JCT
He is practicing his face number 3,
他在練習他臉上的號碼 3,
which he learned from a Lee Marvin movie.
他從李馬文（李馬榮）電影裡面學到的。
His partner, the third person involved,
他的搭檔，那第三個人，
is Arturo,
是Arturo，
from now on ARC, who waits
從現在起ARC，
for the other two in another car.
等著兩個在另一輛車的人。
Precisely at 12:27, he will turn the ignition
在準 12:27不差一秒，他就會啟動點火器
and it will start moving the cylinders.
如此汽缸就會開始運作
There the compression and the spark
那裡的壓力與火花
will generate a tiny explosion
將生成一個小爆炸
that will turn the mix into gas,
並且與汽油融合
which will start the engine.
然後發動機就會被啟動。
But for now the car doesn't start.
但現在這輛車沒有被發動。
As he waits, ARC is thinking.
在他在等待的時候，ARC正在思考著。
If we could dissect his mind,
如果我們能解剖他的頭腦，
we would see
我們將會看到
dozens of fleeting thoughts
幾十個不斷閃過的想法
But maybe I am being indiscreet
但也許我太輕率
All those thoughts lead to the present
所有這些想法導致他
he has bought for his girlfriend.
為他的女朋友買了的禮物。
Nice bow.
這蝴蝶結不錯看吼
At this very moment and nine streets away,
在這個非常時刻，九個街道以外，
a boy is enjoying a car wash experience
一個男孩正在享受他洗車得經驗
Under the same sky,
同一片天空下
small civilisations live oblivious to these facts:
小居民們無視這些生活中事實：
An ant cruises through a crack
一隻 螞蟻號郵輪 通過一條裂縫，
as if it was the Grand Canyon
就像通過大峽谷一樣
And a fly soars over a grocery
一隻蒼蠅飛過一家雜貨店，
as if it was the Amazon Jungle.
就像它是亞馬遜叢林一樣。
But I'm digressing. So much information !
但我離題了。這麼多的資訊 ！
I forgot another element too
我也忘了另一個重要元素
6: A boy that jumps
六： 一個跳躍的男孩
on a dumped mattress.
在這個被跳的床墊上
A few days earlier,
幾天前，
for the first time he didn't feel
這孩子第一次感覺到
like a child when his mother
他不再是孩子了，
took him to the junior floor
當他母親帶他去青少年樓層
instead of the children's.
而不是幼幼區
A few feet up, an office worker
在幾英尺以上，
pours a glass of water.
一位職員到了一杯水
This action coincides with an unexpected spill
這一個舉動恰逢另一個打翻事件
And I know I'm digressing, I know.
而且我知道我又離題，我知道。
But can anyone deny the resemblance
但誰否認這朵雲
of that cloud and Richard Nixon?
和尼克森總統長得真的很像呢 ？
A fraction of the time the cloud took to be formed
要花一點時間才能形成一朵雲
takes a cloud of milk
像雲般的牛奶
to dissolve in Albert's cup of coffee
在Albert's的咖啡裡面瓦解
While he waits, Albert watches TV.
他在等待的時候，Albert 在看電視。
The tragedy on the screen
在螢幕上發生的悲劇讓
makes him wonder what would happen
他不知道還有什麼會發生
if he was in a similar situation right now.
如果他是現在是在類似的情況。
A less harmful explosion
一個危害較小的爆炸
takes place close to him.
在他身旁真的發生了。
Martin always bursts the yolk of the egg
Martin 總是喜歡把蛋黃弄破
with the cap of his favourite sandwich.
就放在他最喜歡的三明治上面。
Beside him, the waiter prepares
在他旁邊侍者為Roman準備了
a hot chocolate for Roman.
一杯熱巧克力。,
who lights another cigarette.
就是正在抽另一根煙的這個人
He thinks it's cool to smoke
他認為只抽
only half cigarettes.
一半的煙很酷。
Let's not judge him.
我們不要評論他這點好了
But let's go back to the focal point of the plot.
但讓我們回到剛剛的情節吧。
It's almost time!
時間差不多了！
ARC's thoughts have become. .
ARC的思緒已經變得.
...a bundle of nerves.
...非常的緊張。
Calmer, JCT is engrossed
比較平靜的JCT，
by a wall stain.
全神貫注的在觀察牆上的污點。.
That reminds him of the map of Australia.
這讓他想起了澳洲的地圖。
I don't know. .
我不知道。.
Maybe we don't need so many details.
也許我們不需要這麼多的細節。
Didn't it all start with a very simple question ?
這一切不是開始於一個非常簡單的問題嗎?
Maybe we will never know
也許我們永遠不會知道
what happened to the bill.
帳單到底發生什麼事情
But… Who really cares ?
但......誰真的在乎阿
THE RUNAWAY